All right. Have you ever thought that
JavaScript was unnecessarily wordy? For
example, look at this. Um, in this code,
I am saying go out and find the input
tag and then add an event listener um
for the key up and then call the handle
change function. In the handle change
function, I want you to go find the P
tag and set its inner HTML equal to the
input tags value. all of that so that I
could say hello world and have it appear
on screen. If you thought that was
unnecessarily um long to type out, I've
got good news for you. There is a
library called jQuery that actually
makes a lot of JavaScript um syntax much
shorter. So um if you want to use
jQuery, um you can see right here is a
URL. Uh this is on cdnjs.com/jquery.
This is the latest version of jQuery.
And to bring it in, we just have to add
our script tag just like we would have
done for Axios. And then we'll do source
and we'll paste in jQuery.
So why is jQuery nice? Well, to do this
exact same thing, let's do it using
jQuery syntax. Rather than having to
type the word document, jQuery lets us
use the dollar sign. The dollar sign um
does and then parenthesis does basically
the exact same thing as document.query
selector. So rather than having to type
all of that,
I just type that. And well, what am I
wanting to select? Well, I want to find
the input. Then what do I want to do?
Well, the next thing I'm doing over here
is I'm adding an event listener for key
up. And here I can say key up. And it's
a function that will attach a function
to it um as soon as this line of code
runs. So what it's doing is it's saying
go find the input box and attach a key
up function.
And if we wanted
this line of code on line 15 to be the
same as line 17, I could just put handle
change. And tada, I've written line 17
on line 15. And they work exactly the
same. Um, but because it's so short, I
figure why not keep going. So, let's
just actually define the change function
in here.
And well, now in this handle change
function, I need to go find the P tag.
Well, how do I find the P tag?
Tada!
I found the P tag. Well, I want to set
its inner HTML. Well, the way you do
that is you call an HTML function. If I
just call this function, it will return
the HTML that's inside of the P tag. If
I want to set the HTML, then I need to
pass in some information to this
function. Well, what do I want to pass
into this function? Well, I want to pass
in the inputs
value. So what I'm doing is I'm saying
go find the input, grab its value, set
the P tags, enter HTML to it whenever
the key up is pushed. And so now on
those few lines of code, I've written
the exact same thing as all of those
lines of code. So if I comment it out
and I come over to my document, I can
say hello world and it types out exactly
like we expected. Some caveats here.
HTML does suffer from the same thing as
this.in inner HTML, which means if I
typed button um and I gave it an on
click
um event where it alerted one and then I
close it and I say hello and then I
close off the button.
Uh this button will run the outside
JavaScript. So this HTML doesn't handle
sanitization. Um, so you'll have to be
aware of all of the same things that you
were aware with in JavaScript. But
jQuery can allow you to shorten
drastically long JavaScript down to just
a few lines. So rather than doing
document.query selector, you can use
this dollar sign. Rather than doing
addeventlister key up, you can just say
key up. And then rather than saying html
equals, you can just call the HTML
function rather than typing out value.
Admittedly, that's about the same number
of characters because um uh you add the
parenthesis instead of finishing the
word value. But still, you get the
picture. JQuery can make your life a lot
easier and it can make your stuff a lot
shorter.
Sometimes jQuery isn't used because it's
not all that difficult to type
document.query selector. And one of the
other reasons jQuery was created was to
handle the difficulty of fetching data.
But now with Axios and fetch, um, that's
actually not as hard as it used to be.
However, all of that being said, jQuery
can save you some lines of code. And so
if you want to use it, you'll just go
out, grab the script tag, and then you
should be able to use jQuery syntax in
your code.